Guide to the New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VII: Correspondence, 1804-1979
  - Subseries VII.3: Subject Files, 1804-1979
    - Location, 1857 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Low Reception, 1867 (Box 231, Folder 23)
    - Madagascar, 1896 (Box 231, Folder 24)
    - Marine Hospital, 1848 (Box 231, Folder 25)
    - Marine Signals, 1846-1864 (Box 231, Folder 26)
    - Marine Surveyor, 1843-1857 (Box 231, Folder 27)
    - Maury, Matthew Fontaine, 1853 (Box 231, Folder 28)
    - Mercantile Marine, 1836-1885 (Box 232, Folder 1)
    - Merchants Coffee House, 1914 (Box 232, Folder 2)
    - Metropolitan Fair, 1864 (Box 232, Folder 3)
    - Mexico, 1838-1878 (Box 232, Folder 4)
    - Mississippi Court Records, 1866-1867 (Box 232, Folder 5)
    - Morse, Samuel F.B.--Death, 1872 (Box 232, Folder 6)
    - National Guard, 1898 (Box 232, Folder 7)
    - National Commerce, 1880-1915 (Box 232, Folder 8)
    - Nautical School, 1867-1906 (Box 232, Folder 9)
    - Navigation
      - 1846-1885 (Box 232, Folder 10)
      - 1847-1894 (Box 232, Folder 11)
    - New York Chamber of Commerce
      - Administrative Records, 1837-1873 (Box 232, Folder 12)
      - Building, 1902-1912 (Box 232, Folder 13)
      - Bronze Building Plaque, 1910-1911 (Box 232, Folder 14)
      - By-Laws, 1843 (Box 232, Folder 15)
      - Meeting Rooms, 1855 (Box 232, Folder 16)
      - Member Resignations, 1863-1870 (2 Folders) (Box 233, Folder 1-2)
      - Monthly Meetings, 1849-1856 (Box 233, Folder 3)
      - Membership Concerns, 1855-1914 (Box 233, Folder 4)
      - Officer Acceptances and Resignations, 1839-1915 (Box 233, Folder 5)
      - Special Meeting Requests, 1838-1914 (3 Folders) (Box 233, Folder 6-8)
    - New York Produce Exchange, 1879 (Box 233, Folder 9)
    - Observatories--New York City, 1847-1859 (Box 233, Folder 10)
    - Police--New York State, 1872-1914 (Box 233, Folder 11)
    - Port of New York Commission, 1914 (Box 233, Folder 12)
    - Privateering, 1854-1862 (Box 233, Folder 13)
    - Protection of Property During War Time, 1859-1860 (Box 234, Folder 1)
    - Public Debt--New York State, 1863-1864 (Box 234, Folder 2)
    - Public Debt--United States, 1890-1891 (Box 234, Folder 3)
    - Public Health, 1880-1914 (Box 234, Folder 4)
    - Quarantine Station--New York City, 1835-1865 (Box 234, Folder 5)
    - Railroads, 1838-1868 (Box 234, Folder 6)
    - Rapid Transit--New York City, 1888-1894 (Box 234, Folder 7)
    - Recovery Efforts After Fire of 1835 1855 (Box 234, Folder 8)
    - Relief Committee--Johnstown, 1889 (Box 234, Folder 9)
    - Relief Fund
      - Russia, 1892 (Box 234, Folder 10)
      - San Francisco, 1908 (Box 234, Folder 11)
    - Resumption of Specie Payments, 1869-1873 (Box 234, Folder 12)
    - Revenue Laws, 1854-1874 (Box 234, Folder 13)
    - Revenue Steam-Cutter Service, 1839-1891 (Box 234, Folder 14)
    - Sailors Hotels and Boarding Houses-Licensing, 1864-1894 (Box 234, Folder 15)
    - Salt Manufacture, 1853 (Box 234, Folder 16)
    - Sanitation--New York City, circa 1900s (Box 234, Folder 17)
    - Seamens’ Retreat-Hospital Tax, 1845 (Box 234, Folder 18)
    - Shipping--United States, 1827-1897 (Box 234, Folder 19)
    - Shipwrecks, 1868-1872 (Box 234, Folder 20)
    - Shipwrecks-Prevention, 1846-1867 (Box 234, Folder 21)
    - Sounding Tubes, 1833-1856 (Box 234, Folder 22)
    - Southern Trade Regulations, 1864-1867 (Box 234, Folder 23)
    - Statue of Liberty, 1886 (Box 234, Folder 24)
    - Street Conditions--New York City, 1868-1920 (Box 234, Folder 25)
    - Sugar, 1879-1881 (Box 234, Folder 26)
    - Taxation, 1864-1915 (Box 234, Folder 27)
    - Tariffs, 1864-1979 (Box 234, Folder 28)
    - Texas, 1843-1901 (Box 234, Folder 29)
    - Tobacco, 1868-1881 (Box 235, Folder 1)
    - Topographical Survey of the State of New York, 1892 (Box 235, Folder 2)
    - Treasury Department, 18[46] (Box 235, Folder 3)
    - Treaties, 1847-1911 (Box 235, Folder 4)
    - Union Defense Committee, 1886 (Box 235, Folder 5)
    - United States Mint--New York City, 1843-1854 (Box 235, Folder 6)
    - United States Navy, 1856-1882 (Box 235, Folder 7)
    - United States Post Office--New York City, 1836-1871 (Box 235, Folder 8)
    - United States Postal Service, 1839-1910 (Box 235, Folder 9)
    - Usury Laws, 1837-1867 (Box 235, Folder 10)
    - Venezuela, 1863-1896 (Box 235, Folder 11)
    - Warden’s Office in the Port of New York, 1852-1857 (Box 235, Folder 12)
    - Warehousing, 1838-1872 (Box 235, Folder 13)
    - Waring Trust-Columbia University, 1899 (Box 235, Folder 14)
    - Washington Monument, 1880-1887 (Box 235, Folder 15)
    - Water Supply, 1905 (Box 235, Folder 16)
    - Weather Data, 1868 (Box 235, Folder 17)
    - Webb Academy, 1889 (Box 235, Folder 18)
    - Weights and Measures
      - 1838-1843 (Box 235, Folder 19)
      - 1839-1858 (Box 235, Folder 20)
    - West Side Improvement, 1915 (Box 235, Folder 21)
    - Wool, 1865 (Box 235, Folder 22)
    - Worlds’ Fair, 1892-1893 (Box 235, Folder 23)
- Series VIII: Member Meeting Minutes, 1768-1973
  The minutes contained in this series, which date back to the Chamber's founding in 1768, offer an intimate look at the key functions of the organization and its involvement in New York City and State business and development throughout the 19th and 20th centuries. These meetings centered on issues that were of significance to local and national commerce, pinpointing how current events would affect business practices. Members used these gatherings as a time to draw attention to their concerns and establish a collective position among the Chamber constituency. Prominent guests were a regular part of each meeting and included state and local politicians, foreign dignitaries, and national luminaries--Herbert Hoover, John D. Rockefeller III, and Frank Lloyd Wright are among several of the iconic figures invited to address the Chamber's monthly meetings over the years. Minutes run continuously from 1768 to 1933 and are documented in oversize bound volumes. Subsequent years are inconsistently represented and are recorded as typescript; minutes from the 1940s are lacking entirely. Administrative documentation and candid photographs for several 20th century guest speakers can be found respectively in Series I: Administration and Series X: Photographs.
  - 1768-1818 (bound volume) (Box 394)
  - 1818-1835 (bound volume) (Box 395)
  - 1836-1846 (bound volume) (Box 396)
  - 1847-1858 (bound volume) (Box 397)
  - 1858-1868 (bound volume) (Box 398)
  - 1868-1874 (bound volume) (Box 399)
  - 1875-1880 (bound volume) (Box 400)
  - 1880-1886 (bound volume) (Box 401)
  - 1886-1892 (bound volume) (Box 402)
  - 1892-1898 (bound volume) (Box 403)
  - 1899-1906 (bound volume) (Box 404)
  - 1906-1912 (bound volume) (Box 405)
  - 1912-1917 (bound volume) (Box 406)
  - 1918-1921 (bound volume) (Box 407)
  - 1921-1923 (bound volume) (Box 408)
  - 1923-1925 (bound volume) (Box 409)
  - 1925-1928 (bound volume) (Box 410)
  - 1928-1933 (bound volume) (Box 411)
  - 1959 (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - 1960, (2 Folders) (Box 205, Folder 2-3)
  - 1961 (Box 205, Folder 4)
  - 1963 (Box 205, Folder 5)
  - 1964, (2 Folders) (Box 206, Folder 1-2)
  - 1965 (Box 206, Folder 3)
  - 1967, (2 Folders) (Box 206, Folder 4-5)
  - 1968 (Box 335, Folder 1)
  - 1969, (2 Folders) (Box 335, Folder 2-3)
  - 1970, (2 Folders) (Box 335, Folder 4-5)
  - 1972 (Box 335, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Notices, 1953 January-1956 May (Box 392, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Notices, 1956 June-1965 January (Box 392, Folder 5)
- Series IX: Printed Materials, 1774-1977
  The printed materials of Series IX encompass a diverse assortment of small pamphlets, leaflets, and booklets intended primarily for limited circulation among a targeted audience. Committee reports, tributes to members, and annual compilations of national chambers of commerce are examples of some of the items found here. A significant portion of Series IX is devoted to a selection of pamphlet publications which have been bound in volumes according to date of issuance. Each volume contains pamphlets on an assortment of topics such as currency, commercial law, defense, and quarantine laws; fold out maps often serve as illustration. Printed materials are organized according to their subject matter or title. For the Chamber of Commerce's more formal publications that were intended for wider distribution, researchers should consult the New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry Publications collection.
  - Pamphlets
    - Catalogue of Portraits, 1924-1941 (Box 337, Folder 2)
    - Chambers of Commerce of the World, 1928 (Box 337, Folder 3)
    - Charter, By-Laws and List of Members, 1951-1962 (Box 337, Folder 4)
    - Commercial Interests
      - International, 1928-1962 (Box 337, Folder 5)
      - New York City, 1916-1977 (Box 337, Folder 6)
      - United States, 1866-1965 (Box 337, Folder 7)
    - Laws of New York from the Year 1691 to 1773 inclusive, 1774 (Box 371, Folder 1)
    - Legislative Directory, 1953-1968 (Box 337, Folder 8)
    - List of Chambers of Commerce in the United States
      - 1920-1939 (Box 337, Folder 9)
      - 1940-1949 (Box 338, Folder 1)
      - 1950-1959 (Box 338, Folder 2)
      - 1960-1969 (Box 338, Folder 3)
    - Memorial
      - Bliss, Cornelius Newton, 1911 (Box 338, Folder 4)
      - Morgan, John Pierpont, 1913 (Box 338, Folder 5)
      - Orr, Alexander E., 1914 (Box 338, Folder 6)
      - Smith, Charles Stewart, 1909 (Box 338, Folder 7)
    - New York Chamber of Commerce Organization
      - Circa 1913-1945 (Box 338, Folder 8)
      - 1956-1970 (Box 338, Folder 9)
    - New York City Promotional Material, 1927-1966 (Box 338, Folder 10)
    - New York State, 1875-1955 (Box 339, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlet Publications
      - 1865 (Box 352)
      - 1866 (Box 467)
      - 1867-1870 (Box 361)
      - 1871-1872 (Box 348)
      - 1873 (Box 365)
      - 1876-1877 (Box 468)
      - 1878-1880 (Box 466)
      - 1881 (Box 363)
      - 1881-1883 (Box 369)
      - 1884 (Box 469)
      - 1885-1886 (Box 470)
      - 1887-1888 (Box 471)
      - 1889-1890 (Box 472)
      - 1891 (Box 473)
      - 1892 (Box 474)
      - 1893-1894 (Box 475)
      - 1895-1897 (Box 356)
      - 1898-1900 (Box 354)
      - 1901-1902 (Box 357)
      - 1903 (Box 355)
      - 1904 (Box 351)
      - 1905 (Box 349)
      - 1906 (Box 353)
    - Reports
      - 1855-1858 (Box 350)
      - 1855-1859 (Box 367)
    - Presentation of the Clinton Vases and Stuart’s Portrait of Washington, 1908 (Box 339, Folder 2)
    - Proceedings on the Presentation of a Gold Medal by the Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York to the Honorable Abram S. Hewitt, 1901 (Box 347)
    - Reports Prepared by the Membership, 1926-1947 (Box 339, Folder 3)
    - Tributes
      - Cleveland, Grover, 1908 (Box 339, Folder 4)
      - Queen Victoria, 1901 (Box 339, Folder 5)
      - Rockefeller, John D., 1950 (Box 339, Folder 6)
      - Simmons, Joseph Edward, 1910 (Box 339, Folder 7)
      - Wilson, George, 1908 (Box 339, Folder 8)
- Series X: Photographs, 1860-1980
  The final series in this collection is comprised largely of photographic prints, though a few photographic slides and glass plate slides are present. A significant portion of these items lack any identifying information and several are undated. Photographs are arranged alphabetically according to subject; a few are oversized. Of particular note are photographs from the Chamber's annual banquet, candid shots of guest speakers at the organization's monthly meetings, and portraits of Chamber members throughout the years.
  - 200th Anniversary
    - General, 1968, (2 Folders) (Box 343, Folder 1-2)
    - Booklet, 1968 (Box 343, Folder 3)
  - Annual Banquet
    - 1929 (Box 343, Folder 4)
    - 1948 (Box 343, Folder 5)
    - 1949 (Box 343, Folder 6)
    - 1950 (Box 343, Folder 7)
  - Arbitration Award, 1942 (Box 343, Folder 8)
  - Ceremony for Designation as a National Historic Landmark, 1980 (Box 343, Folder 9)
  - Chamber of Commerce Buildings, undated (Box 343, Folder 10)
  - Chamber of Commerce Buildings, undated (Box 346, Folder 1)
  - "Chamber of Commerce" Week, undated (Box 343, Folder 11)
  - "Come Back" Pictures, undated (Box 343, Folder 12)
  - Committee on School Sanitation and Equipment--Building Repairs, 1919-1920 (Box 343, Folder 13)
  - Essay Contest Winners, undated (Box 343, Folder 14)
  - Essay Contest Winners, 1945-1962 (Box 343, Folder 15)
  - Gallery Portraits, undated (Box 343, Folder 16)
  - Group Portraits and Candid Photographs
    - Undated (Box 346, Folder 2)
    - Undated (Box 343, Folder 17)
    - 1860 (Box 343, Folder 18)
    - 1921-1950 (Box 346, Folder 3)
    - 1922 (Box 343, Folder 19)
    - 1930-1939 (Box 343, Folder 20)
    - 1940-1947 (Box 343, Folder 21)
    - 1951-1959 (Box 343, Folder 22)
    - 1967 (Box 343, Folder 23)
  - The Hundred Year Association
    - General, undated (Box 344, Folder 1)
    - General, 1957-1976 (Box 344, Folder 2)
    - General, 1968-1975 (Box 344, Folder 3)
    - Annual Dinner, 1959 (Box 344, Folder 4)
    - Annual Dinner, 1961 (Box 344, Folder 5)
  - Inventory, undated (Box 344, Folder 6)
  - Members and Guests
    - Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 344, Folder 7-8)
    - 1930-1939 (Box 344, Folder 9)
    - 1940-1949 (Box 344, Folder 10)
    - 1950-1959, (2 Folders) (Box 344, Folder 11-12)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 345, Folder 1)
    - 1970-1979 (Box 345, Folder 2)
  - New York City, undated (Box 345, Folder 3)
  - New York Port Promotion Association, 1960-1962 (Box 345, Folder 4)
  - New York Yankees Reception, 1967-1971 (Box 345, Folder 5)
  - Paperwork Management Exhibit, 1954 (Box 345, Folder 6)
  - Plans for Grant's Tomb, undated (Box 345, Folder 7)
  - Portraits
    - Undated (Box 346, Folder 4)
    - Undated, (3 Folders) (Box 345, Folder 8-10)
    - 1865-1896 (Box 345, Folder 11)
    - 1941-1949 (Box 345, Folder 12)
    - 1951-1956 (Box 345, Folder 13)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 345, Folder 14)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 345, Folder 15)
  - World Trade Forum, undated (Box 345, Folder 16)
  - Slides--Staff Members, circa 1960s (Box 345, Folder 17)
  - Glass Plate Slides
    - Edison, Thomas--Chamber of Commerce Portrait, undated (Box 376)
    - Tablet--City Hall Subway Station, undated (Box 376)